# Pablo Rodrigo Darde

### Front End Engineer

189 Mário Lacombe St APT 404

Florianópolis SC 88054-260

Brazil

Phone: +55 48 991933 589

E-mail: <a href="mailto:pablodarde@gmail.com">pablodarde@gmail.com</a>

LinkedIn: <a href="https://br.linkedin.com/in/pablodarde">https://br.linkedin.com/in/pablodarde</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/darde">https://github.com/darde</a>

Skype: pablodarde@hotmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Advanced skills with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript. Experience in consuming and developing REST APIs. Knowledge of full stack development with React, Redux, and Mongo DB (NoSql). I'm also working with Native Mobile Apps with React Native, which I have a project published on Github. I work daily with Git and Agile methodologies (Scrum and Kanban). Continuous Integration and Continuous delivery with Heroku, Circle CI, and Jenkins.

#### **Advanced Skills**

- JavaScript ECMA [5, 8] / HTML 5 / CSS3 / jQuery
- React JS with Redux (Unidirectional Data Flow architecture pattern)
- React Native (Native apps for iOS and Android)
- React VR (Virtual Reality Apps with React)
- Testing Stack: Unit testing (Jest/Enzyme, Jasmine, Mocha), Selenium Webdriver,
   Acceptance testing (Cucumber JS)
- Web Development (Responsive Design, Mobile First pattern, Web Standards)
- Clean Code and S.O.L.I.D. principles, Functional programming knowledge
- Micro frontends architectures (Microservices applied to front end)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Resultados Digitais (Florianópolis, SC)

Front-End Engineer (May 2017 - Currently)

Development of React Apps and Ruby on Rails applications.

Daitan Group (Campinas, SP)

Specialist Front-End (May 2016 - May 2017)

Development of React Apps for a security encrypted chat tool.

### SAP (São Leopoldo, RS)

#### **Javascript developer senior (September 2015 - May 2016)**

Accessibility enhancement in complex interfaces by using JAWS screen reader.

### PUCRS (Pontifical Catholic University of Rio Grande do Sul state)

Web Development Manager/Lead Producer (November 2012 – February 2015)

Project planning and management.

#### Web Developer and Flash Programmer (August 2007 – October 2012)

Web development, cross-browser tests, flash programming, and Google APIs programming for PUCRS sites and products.

### **EDUCATION**

# Unicesumar - Centro Universitário de Maringá

Software Engineering Bachelor (2018). In progress

#### UFRGS - Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul - Technical School

Native

Information Systems (2005 – 2007). Complete

# UFRGS - Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

Physics Bachelor (2001 – 2005). Incomplete

write well, read well and speak well

# **LANGUAGES**

English	Portuguese